American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIh. 1892-1896 APS.Archives.IIh APS.Archives.IIh
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 17, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 2p., end. Sends 31 volumes of the Gentleman's Magazine. Asks him to show Franklin MSS. to Cecil Clay.
  - Letter to E[lla M] Morison, May 18, 1893; 3x5-1/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. and add. Concerns invitations.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 19, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Remsen, Ira, 1846-1927
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 2p. and end. Cannot be delegate to the Sesquicentennial Celebration.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, May 20, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Blodget, Lorin, 1823-1901
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. Concerns paper on atmospheric physics which he hopes to have included in memorial volume (APS Proceedings, vol. 32). Encloses hiscard.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 20, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Goodwin, William Watson, 1831-1912
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 2p., and end. Will attend sesquicentennial celebration, as will C.R. Lanman.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 20, 1893; 8x5; Gregory, Emily Ray
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Father, Henry D. Gregory, is ill, and cannot attend Sesquicentennial Celebration.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 20, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends drawings for his paper, "Tertiary Tipulidae, with special reference to those of Florissant, Colorado." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 32, pp. 163-245.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 20, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns printed lists of deficiencies in A.P.S. library. Asks about exchanges of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 21, 1893; 9x4, 8-1/2x6; Sinnickson, Robert, b. 1827
    Trenton, N.J., A.L.S. 10p. and add. 5p. enc. of printed matter. Sends his writings on national philosophy.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, May 22, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Blodget, Lorin, 1823-1901
    Phila., Typed L.S. 2p. Concerns his work on atmospheric physics. A.P.S. Library had material not available elsewhere. Wants to leave his books on subject to A.P.S., with catalogue he has compiled.
  - Note acknowledging gift of flowers for Sesquicentennial celebration, May 22, 1893; 1-1/2x3; Morison, Ella M.
    A.N. on calling card of David Henry Wright 1p.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 23, 1893; 3x5-1/4; Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1831-1908
    Baltimore, A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Gives time of arrival for sesquicentennial meeting.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 23, 1893; 11x8; Philadelphia bureau of press clippings
    Phila., L. 1p. Offers its services. Refers to A.P.S. sesquicentennial anniversary.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips;], May 23, 1893; 6x8, 3-1/2x6-1/2, 2-1/4x3-3/4; Russell, J. H.
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. and add. Enc. of business card Asks for work as stenographer.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, May 24, 1893; 8x5; Lanman, Charles Rockwell, 1850-1941
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copy of the list of delegates to the Sesquicentennial Celebration.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 24, 1893; 8-1/4x5; Pepper, William, 1843-1898
    [Phila.], Typed L.S. 1p. About his sketch of D.H. Agnew. Written below is copy of letter from Phillips to Pepper, Nov. 9, 1893.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 26, 1893; 3-1/4x5-1/4; A. Dulau & Co.
    London, Printed L. filled in in MS., on postal card 1p., end., and add. Asks for titles or wrappers to certain issues of Proceedings in the British Museum.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, May 28, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Hays, Joseph A.
    Pittsburgh, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Requests copy of A.P.S. Constitution and By-Laws.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the APS, Philadelphia, May 29, 1893; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Fisher, Robert J.
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. Sends photo-lithographic copy of APS membership certificate sent to Robert Strettell Jones.
  - Letter to Ella [M.] Morrison [sic], May 29, 1893; 9-1/2x6; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Rye Beach, N.H., A.L.S. 1p. About coal for heating the Hall.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 3, 1893; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends letter from Mrs. M.B. Taft offering book for sale. For enclosure, see Mrs. Taft to Fraley, [1893]
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 10, 1893; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Cresson, Hilborne Thomson
    Karlskuna, Sweden, A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends MS. of paper on "Interpretation of Maya Glyphs by Their Phonetic Element," to be put in A.P.S. files.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 10, 1893; 8x5; Stuart, George, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for Proceedings, No. 135.
  - Letter to Henry Philips, June 13, 1893; Norris, Isaac
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morrison [sic], June 15, 1893; 8x5; Brinton, Daniel Garrison, 1837-1899
    Media, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Ask if A.P.S. receives Boletin de la sociedad economica of Guatemala.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 15, 1893; 3-3/4x6-1/4; G.E. Stechert & Co.
    New York, Typed L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Has package for A.P.S. from Royal Society of Nothern Antiquaries of Denmark.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morison, June 21, 1893; 8x5; Massachusetts Historical Society
    Boston, L.S.: Samuel A[bbott] Green, Librarian. 2p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 26, 1893; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Johns Hopkins University
    Baltimore, L. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns receipt of American chemical journal.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 28, 1893; 8x5; Williamson, Joseph, 1828-1902
    Belfast, Maine, A.L.S. 2p., end. Inquires about obituary notice of Benjamin Vaughan by S.V. Merrick.
  - Letter to Hilborne F. [sic] Cresson, June 29, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    Phila., L. 1p. Copy. Has received his MS. on the Maya glyphs. Refers to Phillips' illness.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], July 6, 1893; 10-1/2x7-3/4, 9x4; Iowa Geological Survey
    Des Moines, Typed L.S.: C[harles] R[ollin] keyes. 1p. and add., end. Asks for entries for a forthcoming bibliography of American palaeontology, 1888-1892.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 8, [1893]; 8x5; Wilson, William P. (William Powell), 1844-1927
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns Hyatt's paper for sesquicentennial volume. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 32, pp. 349-647.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], July 11, 1893; 9x5-1/2; Humphrey, James Ellis, 1861-1897
    Weymouth Heights, Mass., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends Meisel's statement.
  - Letter to Ella [M] Morison, July 11, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Taft, M. B.
    Providence, R.I., A.L.S. 2p. Describes volume of Transactions she offers for sale.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 12, 1893; 6x7-3/4; Hall, Isaac H. (Isaac Hollister), 1837-1896
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends his photograph.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 13, [1893]; 9x5-3/4; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Point Pleasant, N.J., A.L.S. 2p., end. by G.H. H[orn] Concerns his paper on gases. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 17, pp. 149-236.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 13, 1893; 8x5; Rhoads, James E. (James Evans), 1828-1895
    Bryn Mawr, Pa., A.L.S. 2p., end. Acknowledges receipt of publications.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] H[enry] Horn, July 14, 1893; 8x5; Cresson, Hilborne Thomson
    Stockholm, A.L.S. 3p. Enc. Encloses cara with his paris address. Concerns his MS. on Maya glyphs. Refers to Phillips, E.V. Cresson.
  - Letter to [James Cheston] Morris, July 15, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Morison, Ella M.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. with Morris' reply. Enc. wanting. Dr. Horn asks if Morris knows anything about enclosed bill from B. Meisel for plates. For bill, see B. Meisel to A.P.S., April 5, 1893.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 15, 1893; 3x5; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L. on postal card, filled in in MS. 1p. and add. Concerns shipment of packages.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 17, 1893; 8x5; McKenna, Thomas P.
    Long Branch, N.J., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for particulars on the Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 18, 1893; 11x8-1/2; Storrs Agricultural Experiment Station
    Storrs, A.L.S.: C[harles] S[hepherd] Phelps. 1p. Concerns Proceedings No. 141.
  - Letter to F[rancis] C[lifford] Phillips, July 18, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    L. 1p Copy. Concerns his papers on gases. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 17, pp. 149-236.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 18, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Rowland, Kate Mason, d. 1916
    Newport, R.I., A.L.S. 2p., end. Inquires about material on Charles Carroll of Carrollton.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 20, 1893; 3-3/4X6-1/4; Macmillan & Co.
    New York, L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Asks name of A.P.S. librarian.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 20, 1893; 3-3/4x6-1/4; New York Hospital
    New York, L. on postal card, S.: Jos. H. Vandervoort Asst. Librarian. 1p. and add. About Proceedings, No. 140.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morrison [sic], July 21, 1893; 8-1/4x5; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Directs her to prepare a receipt for loan of Roberts photographs to M.B. Snyder.
  - Receipt for Roberts collection of star photographs, July 21, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Snyder, Monroe Benjamin, 1848-1932
    Phila., A.D.S. 1p., end.
  - Letter to J[ames] E[llis] Humphrey, July 25, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    Phila., Asks for further information about bill from B. Meisel for plates.
  - Letter to B[erthold] Meissel [sic], July 25, 1893; 9x5-1/2, 8x5; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    Phila., L. 1p. Copy. Enc. Returns Meisel's bill for balance due on plates of Humphrey's paper. Asks for itemized statement.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 28, 1893; 11x8-1/4, 5-1/2x5-3/4; Grant, Thomas P.
    Louisville, Ky., A.L.S. 1p. and note. Inquiry about John Julian as a member, with copy of Phillips' (?) reply.
  - Letter to H[ilborne] T[homson] Cresson, July 28, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    Phila., L. 2p. Copy. Concerns his MS. on the Maya glyphs.
  - Letter to E[lla M.] Morison, July 28, 1893; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    [Atlantic City, N.J.,]. A.L.S. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Concerns Phillips prize circular. Send some to Emily Phillips.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], July 29, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Hoppin, J. M. (James Mason), 1820-1906
    Litchfield, Conn., A.L.S. 3p., end. by G.H. H[orn]. Inquires about proof of his paper on "The Philosophy of Art, " read at the Sesquicentennial Celebration. For printed paper, see: APS proceedings, Vol. 32, pp. 56-76.
  - Letter to [George Henry Horn], July 29, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Humphrey, James Ellis, 1861-1897
    Weymouth Heights, Mass., A.L.S. 2p. Explains B. Meisel's bill for plates, which were for his paper on Saprolegniaceae. Refers to H. Phillips. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 18, pp. 63-148.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 30, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Coues, Elliott, 1842-1899
    Cranberry, N.C., A.L.S. 1p., end., and end. Will return Lewis and Clark journals next month, when his new edition has been published. Edition promises to be a great success.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July, 1893; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Académie royale des sciences, des lettres et des beaux-arts de Belgique
    Bruxelles, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Marchal, Le Secrétaire Perpétual 1p., end. In French Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 1, 1893; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Peoria, Ill. Law library association
    Peoria, L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Asks for particulars on Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 2, 1893; 10-1/2x8; American Historical Association
    Washington, Typed L.S.: A. Howard Clark, Assistant Secretary. 1p., end. Inquires about A.P.S. collections of historical objects. For gist of reply, see P. DuBois to H. Phillips, Oct. 13, 1893.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 2, 1893; 11x8-1/2; Emerson, George D.
    Buffalo, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 5, 1893; 9-3/4x8; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    Stevenson, Va., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about proof of his paper on Pennsylvania German customs. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 32, pp.325-331.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, August 8, 1893; 8x5; Henry, Joseph J.
    Muncey, Ont., Canada, A.L.S. 3p. Inquires about work of David Zeisberger on languages of the Iroquois, Mohegans, Delawares and Onandagas.
  - Letter to Miss Ella Morrison [sic], Aug. 11, 1893; 10-1/2x7-3/4; Cresson, Emlen V.
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns H.T. Cresson's MS. on Maya glyphs.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 11, 1893; 3x5; Luzac & Co. (London, England)
    London, L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Orders copy of Hilprecht's Old Babylonian inscriptions. Refers to M. Jastrow.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morison, Aug. 13, 1893; 9-3/4x8; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    Petoskey, Mich., A.L.S. lp. Gives address to which to send proof of his paper on Pennsylvania German customs. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 32, pp. 325-331.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 15, 1893; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Rudolph indexer co., Chicago
    Chicago, Typed L. 1p., end. Asks for copy of last Annual Report.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 18, 1893; 11x7-1/2; Smith, George H.
    Los Angeles, Cal., Typed L.S. 2p., end. Asks for particulars about Phillips prize essay. Is sending copies of his books on legal subjects.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 18, 1893; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Société royale de géographie d'Anvers
    Antwerp, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edm. Lombaerts. 2p.,end. In French. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 21, 1893; 8x5; Green, Samuel A. (Samuel Abbott), 1830-1918
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks to see proof of his paper on "Benjamin Franklin, Printer, Patriot, and Philosopher," read at Sesquicentennial celebration. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 32, pp.42-54.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Aug. 24, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Hopes his health will now permit him to answer questions, for which see T. Williams to H. Phillips, May 20, 1893.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 29, 1893; 7x5; Weatherly, Edward Christopher, 1855-1934
    San Francisco, [Cal.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for particulars on Phillips essay prize.
  - Letter to Miss Ella Morrison [sic], Aug. 29, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Asks for copies of printed lists of deficiencies in A.P.S. library.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 5, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns lists of deficiencies in A.P.S. Library.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 6, 1893; 8x5; Perkins, D. W. (David Walter), b. 1851
    Utica, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for copy of membership list to forward to English publisher, Elliott Stock.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 6, 1893; 3-3/4x6-1/4; Simmons, C. A.
    Elmira, N.Y., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add., end. Asks for particulars about Phillips essay prize.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 7, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., Typed L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting. Concerns filling gaps in library's sets of transactions. Presents suggestion for library committee. Sends note on Royal Geographical Society.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society;], Sept. 8, 1893; 11x8; Philadelphia bureau of press clippings
    Phila., L. 1p. Offers its services in connection with the Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Sept. 14, 1893; 11x8; Texas. Attorney-General's Office
    Austin, [Texas], Typed L.S. with stamp: C.A. Culberson, Attorney General. 2p., end. Inquires about Lewis Bringier's map of Louisiana. Refers to those by William Darby, John Melish.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 16, 1893; 3x5; Lyman, Benjamin Smith, 1835-1920
    [Phila.], A.L.S. on postal card. 1p., end., and add. Announces death of Edward Hopper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 20, 1893; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 2p. Appoints C.S. Dolley to prepare obituary of Maisch. Refers to R. Cornelius.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Sept. 20, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Gilman, Daniel Coit, 1831-1908
    Baltimore, A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns Publication of his paper on "Present Aspects of Science in America," read at Sesquicentennial Celebration. For description of paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 32, p.33.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Sept. 22, 1893; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Currier, Charles F. A.
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about Phillips essay competition.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Sept. 24, 1893; 10x8; Lyman, Benjamin Smith, 1835-1920
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper on the great Mesozoic fault in New Jersey. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 31, pp. 246-47, 314-317.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Sept. 25, 1893; 11x8-1/2; Canfield, George L. (George Lewis), 1866-
    Detroit, Mich., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips essay competition.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Sept. 25, 1893; 10-1/4x8; Heyer, W. D.
    Elizabeth [N.J.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for information about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 29, 1893; 3x5-1/4; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. and add. Has already sent Bolton's Bibliography of chemistry.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 30, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Wants to discuss library matters.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Sept. 30, 1893; 8x5; Parsons, Eugene
    Chicago, A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for particulars on Phillips prize.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Sept. 30, 1893; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Phillips, Francis C. (Francis Clifford), 1850-1920
    Allegheny, Pa., A.L.S. 2p., and end. Concerns errors in his paper on gases. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol. 17, pp. 149-236.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 2, 1893; 8x5-1/2; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Asks to submit paper on fossil mammals of the Deep River formation. For printed paper, see: A.P.S. Transactions, vol. 18, pp. 55-185.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 3, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Arranges meeting.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 4, 1893; 9-1/4x6; Oliver, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), b. 1853
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for blanks.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 4, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Wallerstein, David
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for particulars about Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Oct. 4, [1893?]; 7X4-1/2; Michael, Helen Abbott, 1857-1904
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks him for a service.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 5, 1893; 5-1/4x8-1/4; Willoughby, W. W.
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Asks for particulars about Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 6, 1893; 6-1/2x8-1/4; Königlich Sächsisches Meteorologisches Institut
    L. 1p., end. In German. Receipt of Proceedings.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 6, 1893; United States. House of Representatives
    1 postcards. Regarding documents. U.S. House of Representatives.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Oct. 6, 1893; 8x5; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Sends nomination papers for Henry A. DuPont.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 12, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 2p. Returns copy of Brackenridge's Modern Chivalry. Discusses composition of committee appointed to consider Williams' resolution calling for an index to the Transactions.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society;]:, Oct. 12, 1893; 10-1/2x8, 3-1/2x6-1/4; Indian Rights Association
    Phila., Typed L. 1p. and add., end. Offers its publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 12, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, [N.J.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns drawings for his paper. Refers to H.F. Osborn, Werner & Winter.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 12, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., Typed L.S. 2p. and end. Enc. wanting. Sends bookseller's list of quotations, and discusses ways to fill gaps in A.P.S. holdings. For enclosure, see R.M. Lindsay, List of bookseller's quotations [Oct., 1893]
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 13, 1893; 5-1/2x8-1/4; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Returns letter of inquiry from American Historical Association, and gives gist of his reply. For inquiry, see Amer. Hist. Assoc. to A.P.S., Aug. 2, 1893.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Oct. 16, 1893; 9-1/2x6; Keane, John J. (John Joseph), 1839-1918
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Will send his photograph.
  - Bill for books, Oct. 16, 1893; 7x8-3/4; J. B. Lippincott Company
    Phila., Printed D. filled in in MS. 1p.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Oct. 18, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 2p. Enc. wanting. Encloses T. Williams' letter about committee on his resolution concerning an index of Transactions. Discusses composition of committee. Refers to Brinton.
  - Letter to Alpheus Hyatt, Boston, Oct. 23, 1893; 7-1/4x8-1/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    [Phila.] L. 1p. Copy. Concerns his drawings for paper on "Phylogeny of an acquired characteristic." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 32, pp. 349-647.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, Phila., Oct. 24, 1893; 10-1/2x8; Fairview institute and commercial college
    Gibsonville, N.C., A.L.S.: W.T. Whitsett, Supt. 1p. Asks for particulars on Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Oct. 24, [1893]; 7x4-1/2; Morris, John G. (John Gottlieb), 1803-1895
    A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper on American historical societies, Presented to the A.P.S. sesquicentennial celebration. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 32, pp. 76-83.
  - Letter to Sam[ue]l H[ubbard] Scudder, Oct. 25, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., L. 1p. Draft. B. Meisel of Boston will do plates for his paper on tertiary Tipulidae. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 32, pp. 163-245.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Oct. 26, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Nolan, Edward James, 1846-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks if his assistant may copy some references.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 26, 1893; 8x5; Scudder, Samuel Hubbard, 1837-1911
    Cambridge, [Mass.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper on tertiary Tipulidae. Refers to B. Meisel. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 32, pp. 163-245. Written on same sheet is Phillips' reply See [Phillips] to [Scudder], Oct. 28, 1893.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Oct. 27, 1893; 9x5-3/4; Blodget, Lorin, 1823-1901
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Concerns illustrations for his paper on atmospheric physics. Refers to Mac-Calla and Co.
  - Letter to J[ohn] S[ergeant] Price, Oct. 28, 1893; 7x4-1/2; Allison, Joseph, 1819-1896